Martha Sharpe

Software Engineer

marthasharpe2020@gmail.com marthacodes.com

github.com/marthasharpe linkedin.com/in/marthasharpe2020

Summary

I am a self-taught developer specializing in React and React Native. I love writing quality code, learning new tools, and solving interesting problems.

Tech Stack

JavaScript | TypeScript | React | React Native | Redux | GraphQL | REST | Git | GitHub | Jest

Work History

Software Engineer, Canopy Servicing Inc. - Remote

March 2022 - current

- Built a web platform for borrowers to submit and track financing requests using React Remix
- Maintained and improved a web platform for lenders built with Next.js
- Created custom ui components for a library used by both platforms with Tailwind.css
- Worked to clarify and prioritize requirements and create Linear tickets for the front end team
- Worked closely with backend engineers and designers to speed up latency and improve user experience for both platforms

Software Engineer, Starship HSA - Remote

March 2021 - Jan 2022

- Worked on a scrum team to develop new features for a Health Savings Account mobile app
- Built features using React Native for iOS, Android and web, and a custom component library
- Used React Relay for data-fetching from a GraphQL API and Zustand state management
- Wrote UI tests with Detox, and unit tests with React Native Testing Library and Jest

Frontend Engineer, Grassp Health - Remote

June 2020 - Feb 2021

- Responsible for designing and building a cross-platform mobile app for delivery drivers
- Used React Native with Expo-cli, Redux with a custom middleware, and TypeScript
- Implemented background location tracking, push notifications, and map routing
- Prepared the app for deployment as an enterprise app and oversaw distribution
- Wrote docs for the app on GitHub and tests using Jest and React Native Testing Library

React-Native Developer, *Freelance - Remote*

May - June 2020

- Built a cross-platform mobile app using React Native and the Expo SDK
- Responsible for designing and building the front end to communicate with the REST API
- Implemented user login, access to camera, and social media sharing options
- Communicated with the client to determine requirements and meet expectations

Web Developer, Business of Healthcare - Remote

March - May 2020

- Built a multimedia website using Squarespace
- Brainstormed design options with the business owner
- Integrated third-party services such as Eventbrite and Mailchimp
- Set up embedded live-stream and live-chat capabilities

Education

University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

- BA in Classical Studies. Honors Scholar
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude